Wai Law

WEB DESIGN | FRONT END

T: +44(0)7765 037386 E: HELLO@WAILAW.ME W: WAILAW.ME ADDRESS: FLAT 2, 9 WINTHORPE ROAD, LONDON, SW15 2LW.

PROFILE

Creative professional experienced in a range of web disciplines with an eye for design and a passion for development. Enthusiastic about new industry techniques and applying them in practice. An efficient project manager who consistently delivers high quality work to schedule.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

RESPONSIVE DESIGN, HTML5, PAGE OPTIMISATION, CLIENT SIDE DEVELOPMENT, WIRE-FRAMING, USER EXPERIENCE, PROJECT MANAGEMENT, EMAIL DEVELOPMENT, VIDEO EDITING, CSS3, VERSION CONTROL - GITHUB, BOOTSTRAP, ZURB FOUNDATION, PHOTOSHOP, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, WORDPRESS, STUDIOPRESS GENESIS, SASS, JEKYLL, MARKDOWN,

OTHER SKILLS

- Experience of building a digital marketing strategy
- Managing content production and digital projects
- Supervising a team
- Collaboration with directors, product managers, design and development teams
- Delivering high quality work to strict deadlines

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

FRONT END DEVELOPER, CUBA DIRECT/TRAVEL DIRECT/CUBA DIRECT US, LONDON; MAR 2016-PRESENT

Focussed on front end design and co-marketing page development. Continued improvement to user experience and page optimisation. I project manage and take the lead on design concepts. Also responsible for email development, cross-browser testing and development of page templates in Axinom and Umbraco CMS.

Achievement: Designed and developed Travel Direct and Cuba Direct US front ends. Redesigned key pages of Cuba Direct UK using data research and testing to improve user experience and engagement resulting in a 25% decrease in the bounce-rate in the first week post launch.

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER, <u>WWW.WAILAW.ME</u>, LONDON; 2014-PRESENT In my spare time I work on additional web projects. Specialising in the creation of premium travel and leisure related websites. I can help your website to engage your users better, convert on more occasions, ensure the best experience and increase revenue. Responsible for design research, data analysis, client side functionality, user experience, code, testing, maintenance and ensuring cross-browser compatibility.

Achievement: Developed a productised service helping small businesses to get online quickly using our website in a week solution.

FRONT END DESIGN & WEB CONTENT, COX & KINGS TRAVEL, LONDON; OCT 2010-MAR 2016

Responsible for content planning and strategy and project managing developments. Client side design and creation of landing pages for co-marketing promotions. Assisting with email development. Creating new initiatives for the Cox & Kings website to continuously improve overall user experience and interaction, achieving longer visit times and lower bounce rates. Worked on the development of the new company website in 2014. Collaborate with the Digital Manager to decide on the most suitable presentation of content in specific sections of the website. Production of digital content such as e-books and online maps. Edit and manage video content.

Achievement: Developed a strategy and workflow that streamlined the process of getting content online resulting in, greater efficiency and increased productivity.

WEB DESIGN CONSULTANT, ACTIV WEB DESIGN, HAMPSHIRE

AUG 2007-10/2010

Building websites for small businesses. Consulting on the most suitable solution. Design planning, wire-framing, markup and styles. Initiate ideas and project manage.

Achievement: This was a franchise model and my first time running a business. I had to sustain a flow of clients, market myself, generate leads, as well as producing websites.

USER END TRAINER, KONICA MINOLTA BUSINESS SOLUTIONS, HAMPSHIRE MAR 2006-2007

Providing operational training on print production systems

Training on software and drivers

Assisting the engineer with networking

Assisting with Pre-Sales advising on product types and technical solutions Assisting with post sale technical problem solving and maintenance issues

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NORTHAMPTON

BA BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION & MANAGEMENT 2000, 2:2.

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENT

Sep 2015, Completed the Shine Night Walk for Cancer Research. A marathon distance walk through the streets of London, through the night. TIME: 10 HOURS.

REFERENCES

Available on request